Alaska
止まろう　逃げきれない
Let's stop. We'd never get away.
ミスタ・カリウム　目標を発見しました
Mr. Kalium, we located the target.
ミスタ・カリウム？
"Mr. Kalium"...?
This is our first time meeting like this, Gavin Hunter.
こうして会うのは初めてだな　ギャビン・ハンター
バカな　あなたは
This can't be! You're...
カリーニン少佐　なぜあなたが敵に
Lieutenant Commander Kalinin!
Why are you with the enemy?!
It happens all the time in this business.
この業界ではよくあることだ
Building something like this won't change anything.
こんなものを作ったところで何も変わらない
無駄な労力だったな
It was a waste of effort.
少佐　たくさんの味方が殺されたはずだろう
Lieutenant Commander,
many of your allies must have been killed!
それが　なんという破廉恥な
This is so shameless!
Don't you feel any pain over it?!
少しは胸が痛まないのか
I didn't know why we'd received our lives
why we all had come into this world
I didn't know how to face the one beside
only I looked away and wandered where to love
only I looked away and wandered where to love though it was always by my side
though it was always by my side
If I have a tough, iron armor protecting the world
I wonder if I can see you, and beyond
I just want to be stronger than anything
I just want to be stronger than anything to hold you, all of, oh even the heart
to hold you, all of, oh even the heart
All the dreams end up as mere dreams, even if game's over
All the dreams end up as mere dreams,
even if game's over, I won't give up my hope
I won't give up my hope
Even a hope may be said 'Just that's a thought'
so I still want to reach for you hoping you live your soul
Only there's a truth
Only there's a truth. Living for making all the moments shine with proving all times. Just seeing your smiles,
Living for making all the moments shine with proving all times
Just seeing your smiles, that's my dream
that's my dream
Even if we're all even in the dark
Northern Florida
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品  仅供学习交流  禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕  尽在 www.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
Stormy Night
Episode 11
日听&日校：小伍 gen   翻译&校对：mam 小江   时间轴：鸭鸭   压制：結城結衣
When did you...?
いつの間に
死体はしゃべるな
No chatter from corpses.
全滅だ　相良にやられっぱなしだった
We got wiped out. Sagara bested us again and again.
これぐらいできないと　アマルガムとは戦えない
If I can't manage this much, I can't fight Amalgam.
Well, this means you've recovered for the most part.
まあ　おおむね回復したわけだね
そこで　新情報だ
And I have new information.
ニケーロ
Nicelo.
クラマが口にしていた地名の一つだ
It's one of the locations Kurama mentioned.
ようやく絞り込めた
I finally managed to narrow it down.
メキシコ南部か
Southern Mexico, eh?
There's a mansion on this shoreline
that doesn't appear on maps.
ここの沿岸に地図には載っていない邸宅がある
なぜアマルガムの関連施設だと
What makes you think it's an Amalgam facility?
The flow of money, and logistics service providers.
金の流れと物流業者　あれやこれや
The way certain things are handled
is very similar to Namsac.
やり口がナムサクとよく似てるんだよ
厳重な警備だ
Security is tight.
That's an Alastor.
アラストルだ
Those miniature AS things?
小型のASだっけ
タフな相手だ　俺の部隊もひどく手こずった
They're tough opponents.
My unit had a really hard time with them.
That's a pain.
厄介だな
だが　問題はむしろこっちだ
But the real problem is actually over here.
このコンテナがどうしたんだ
What's the deal with these containers?
Those are disguised AS containers.
ASの偽装コンテナだな
以前　ネバダの兵器ショーで見たことがある
I saw some once at a weapons show in Nevada.
They're probably Codarl types.
おそらくコダールタイプだ
The ones equipped with Lambda Drivers or whatever?
ラムダ・ドライバとかいうのを搭載してるやつか
Whoa, hey, is this going to work?
おいおい　大丈夫なのかよ
俺一人でなんとかするつもりだ
I intend to find some way by myself.
There you go again.
またそうやって…
いい加減一匹狼を気取るのはやめてくれよ
Stop acting like you're some lone wolf!
だいたいこの情報だっていろんな…
Other people worked to provide you with--
要するにだ
Long story short.
All we have to do is f**k those
Codarl things with a surprise AS attack.
そのコダールだかをASで奇襲して　ファッ〇ちまえばいいんだろが
If only it were that easy.
それができれば苦労しません
俺たちにゃその肝心のASがないんですよ
We're missing one vital thing: an AS!
M9は無理でも　せめて現用の第二世代があれば
Even if an M9 is out of the question,
if we at least had one of the current second-generations...
だったらいけそうだ
Then it could work.
See!
な
It's the latest M6 model.
M6の最新モデルだ
しかも特殊部隊仕様だぜ
And it's special forces issue, too.
ちょろいもんよ　コネを総動員したからな
Piece of cake. I put all my connections to work on it.
コネ？
Connections?
Who's he?
誰
わしのダチだ
A pal of mine.
アメリカ海軍のロイ・シールズ大佐だ
Captain Roy Seals, of the US Navy.
I had a female superior officer...
俺の上官だった女性の　なんというかその…
...and he's her... um...
Big fan?
大ファン
それです
Yes, that.
ジョン・コートニー
John Courtney!
さあ　言われた通り　書類に細工して持ってきてやったぞ
See? Like you asked, I doctored
the paperwork and brought it along!
さあ　テッサたんはどこかな
Now! Where's Lil' Tessa at?
Uh, yeah, about Lil' Tessa...
テッサたんは　それが…
いないんじゃ
She ain't here.
No!
ノー
Mexican Coastal Waters
敵の増援？
Enemy reinforcements?
We cannot be sure.
確定はしていません
ですが　近海に不審な音源を探知しています
But we've detected suspicious
audio sources in coastal waters.
ベヘモス
Behemoths.
あるいは
Perhaps.
作戦を中止しますか
Shall we suspend the operation?
艦長
Captain?
そうね
Yes...
But we will carry out reconnaissance.
でも　偵察は行います
クルーゾーさんを呼んで
Contact Mr. Clouseau.
State of Michoacán, Mexico
ミスタ・シルバー
Mr. Silver?
聞いているのかね　ミスタ・シルバー
Are you listening, Mr. Silver?
ええ　何か
Yes. What is it?
君が握っているあの娘　千鳥かなめのことだ
It's about that girl in your
possession, Kaname Chidori.
あのミスリルの残党軍は君らの居場所を嗅ぎつけた形跡がある
There are signs those Mithril remnants
have gotten wind of your whereabouts.
それが何か
And what about it?
カリオペ計画にはあの娘が不可欠だ
The girl is indispensable for Project Calliope.
移動すべきでは
Shouldn't she be moved?
今の彼女には落ち着く場所が必要です
What she needs now is a place where she can feel calm.
ならば　こちらからも増援を派遣しろ
Then I'll dispatch reinforcements from here as well.
ベヘモスとコダールを3機ずつ
Behemoths and Codarls, three each.
大兵力ですね
That's a large force.
Although I do appreciate the sentiment.
お気持ちはありがたいのですが
You have some reason to turn it down?
断る理由があるのかね
No. Do as you please.
いいえ　ご随意に
Master Leonard. Mr. Kalium has arrived.
レナード様　ミスタ・カリウムがご到着です
Have you been waiting long, Mr. Kalium?
待ったかな　ミスタ・カリウム
いえ
No.
初任務の感想は
Any thoughts about your first mission?
特には
None in particular.
鹵獲した機体は
What of the mech we captured?
見ようか
I'll take a look.
This is their secret weapon?
これが彼らの切り札ですか
失望したかい
Are you disappointed?
いえ
No.
The core unit has already been removed.
すでにコアユニットは外してあります
こちらです
It's over here.
Is this definitely it?
間違いありませんか
How well prepared...
用意周到だね
Is something amiss?
何か
いや　これでいいよ
No. I've seen enough.
処分して
Dispose of it.
会議はいかがでしたか
How did the meeting go?
As I expected. It seems they're
sending some support our way.
予想通りだよ
こちらに支援を回してくれるそうだ
支援を名目にここを襲ってくると
When in reality, they're going to attack?
そうなるように誘ったんだ　来るさ
I lured them into doing it.
It will come.
Or rather, it might already be close at hand.
いや　もうそこまで来ているかもしれない
And in concert with movements from above,
上の動きに抗して　米軍の特殊作戦コマンドが動く気配もあります
there are signs of movements within
US Special Operations Command.
I'd heard Amalgam has a firm grasp
on the US military's movements.
アマルガムは米軍の動向も掌握していると聞いたが
一部をね
At least in part.
期待はしすぎないほうがいい
You shouldn't get your hopes up too high.
なるほど
That figures.
ずいぶんと待たせるじゃないか
You sure kept me waiting long enough.
Sorry, Caspar.
すまないね　カスパー
So he's the one?
そいつが例の？
He's Mr. Kalium. Also known as--
ミスタ・カリウムだ　またの名を…
知ってる
I know who he is. He's famous in this world.
この世界じゃ有名人さ
私も君のことは知っているよ
I know who you are, too.
世界屈指の狙撃兵と　こんなところで会えるとはな
I never expected to meet one of
the world's best snipers here.
これで全員揃いましたか
Everyone is now present?
ああ　では
Yes, so let's get started on the welcoming party.
歓迎委員会を始めようか
Outskirts of Nicelo
ワンミニッツ
One minute!
This is call sign Uruz 7.
こちらコールサイン　ウルズ7
I'm about to begin my drop.
これより降下を開始する
了解　ウルズ7　幸運を
Roger. Good luck, Uruz 7.
What do you want?
何の用
身支度をしておいてほしい
I want you to get ready.
We're probably leaving here tonight.
おそらく今夜中にここを離れる
So you can't tell the caged bird anything.
籠の中の小鳥には何も話せないってわけね
I'll tell you at some point.
いずれ話すよ
A storm is coming.
嵐が来るわ
A storm.
嵐よ
嵐か
That's convenient.
好都合だ
An enemy? No...
敵　いや
An M9?
M9？
M9　ミスリルの機体か
M9? Is it a Mithril mech?
No, I don't know this model.
いや　知らない機種だ
米軍のM9だな　たぶん陸軍の連中だろう
It's a US military M9. Probably some Army unit.
So, they've finally put them into combat.
ああ　いよいよ実戦配備か
It doesn't look like they're here for us, at least.
少なくともこちらが目当てじゃなさそうだ
Even so, this is odd.
だとしても　妙ですよ
The US AS got taken out.
米軍のASがやられた
So much for a surprise attack.
The operation's suspended. Withdraw.
もう奇襲は無理だ
作戦は中止　撤収
いや
No.
Now's the only chance, while the
enemy's busy with the US forces.
敵が米軍に気を取られている今しかない
無茶だ　引き返せ　宗介
It's too dangerous. Turn back, Sousuke!
まだ間に合う　間に合わせる
I'll still be in time. I have to be!
Chidori! Just a little longer!
千鳥　あと少しなんだ
宗介
Sousuke!
He killed the connection.
通信を切りおった
I'm pulling out Bardet's support team.
バルデの別働隊は下がらせます
このままでは彼らも危険だ
At this point they're in danger, too.
Mr. Lemon!
レモンさん
Enemies?
敵？
Doesn't look that way.
そうは見えんな
Hold your fire!
撃つな
Here, too...
ここにも
Wow, that was painful to watch.
ったく　見れたもんじゃなかったわね
そんな機体で何しに来たの
What're you doing here in a mech like that?
マオ
Mao!
宗介　やっぱりあんたね
Sousuke, I figured it was you.
使ってる周波数が同じだったからね
You were using the same frequency. We were listening in.
聞き耳立ててたってわけ
駄々漏れなんだよ
We heard everything.
The guy on the other end kept going "Sousuke, Sousuke!"
相手のやつが宗介　宗介って
Kurz!
クルツか
Hah! You're still alive, you gloomy bastard!
生きてやがったな　このネクラ男が
なぜここに
Why are you here?
積もる話もいろいろあるけど　どうやら新手が来たみたい
There's plenty for us to talk about,
but it looks like more enemies are here.
情報を送るわ
I'll send you the data.
Two Codarl types. I don't think
surprise attacks will work anymore.
コダールタイプが2機　もう奇襲は効かないでしょうね
Sousuke, as for you...
宗介　あんたは
問題ない
No problem.
Let's take them out here.
ここで叩こう
Let's show them how experts get it done!
玄人の味を見せてやろうぜ
Fine by me. You guys are ready, right!
上等　野郎ども　覚悟はいいわね
Any time!
いつでも
Anywhere!
どこでも
ロックンロール
Rock and roll!
Over here!
こっちだ　忍者野郎
Ninja bastard!
That's one down.
まず1機
Kurz!
クルツ
That's not the way you're supposed to go, is it?
あんたが行くのはそっちじゃないでしょう
マオ
Mao?
だから駄々漏れなんだって
Like we said, we heard everything.
わけは知らないけど　行かなきゃなんないんでしょう
I don't know the reason, but don't you have to go?
Chidori... is over there.
あそこに千鳥がいる
Kaname is?
かなめが
彼女を助けたい
I want to rescue her.
All right. Leave this here to us.
わかった　ここは任せて
すまない
Thanks.
Jeez.
ったく
This is Uruz 2. We've defeated two Codarl types.
こちらウルズ2　コダールタイプ2機を撃破
Currently in combat with the remaining one.
残り1機と交戦中
Furthermore, upon encountering the enemy,
we confirmed that Sousuke Sagara is alive.
なお　敵と遭遇した際　相良宗介の生存を確認
相良さんが
Mr. Sagara is?!
ピンピンしてたわ
Alive and kicking.
Looks like he has the same objective as us.
どうやらこっちと目標は同じ　かなめがそこにいるみたい
And looks like Kaname is there.
Understood. You be careful, too.
わかりました　あなたも気をつけて
大丈夫よ　交信終了
I'll be fine. Ending transmission.
相良さん　よかった
Mr. Sagara... Thank goodness.
Asshole!
野郎
Ben!
ベン
Sorry for the wait.
待たせた
This is Uruz 7. Éphémère 1, do you copy?
こちらウルズ7　エヘメル1聞こえるか
Sousuke! You're okay!
宗介　無事だったか
肯定だ
Affirmative.
ミスリルの戦友と合流して　コダール2機を撃破した
I was joined by my Mithril buddies,
and we destroyed two Codarls.
戦友だって　信用できるのか
Buddies? Can we trust them?
保証する
I guarantee it.
I have some news, too.
Someone made contact with us earlier.
こちらもニュースだ
さっきコンタクトしてきた人物がいて
Huh?
A woman named Wraith.
レイスって女性だ　予備のASを用意してくれた
She provided us with a spare AS.
If you run into trouble,
we'll be on standby at coordinate 41a.
ヤバそうなら　座標は41Aで待機を
Chidori!
千鳥
I swear it!
必ず…
Chidori!
千鳥
What about the US forces?
米軍のほうは
Looks like they withdrew.
Their morale seemed low.
撤収したようだ
士気は低いように見えた
それより
Never mind that...
敵
Enemies?!
8時の方向
Bearing, 8:00!
まだいやがった
There were more of them.
そのようね
Looks that way.
Watch out.
気をつけろ
They're different than the earlier enemies.
さっきの敵とは違うぞ
待っていたよ
We've been waiting.
Welcome.
ようこそ　ようこそミスリル残党の諸君
Welcome, remnants of Mithril.
ファウラーか
Fowler?!
I take my hat off to all your strenuous efforts,
君たちの奮闘には敬意を表するが　我々もそろそろ終わりにしたいのでね
but we'd like to go ahead and put an end to this now.
And there you have it.
そういうわけ
You'd best be ready!
覚悟してもらおうか
包囲は完了している　武器を捨てろ
You're fully surrounded! Drop your weapon.
That voice...
この声は…
少佐
Lieutenant Commander?
ヘルマジスタンを思い出すな　相良宗介
This reminds me of Helmajistan, Sousuke Sagara.
少佐　これはいったい…
Lieutenant Commander! What the hell is this?!
見ての通りだ　私はアマルガムの人間になった
It's what it looks like. I've joined Amalgam.
If you resist, I'll order them to gun you down.
抵抗するなら射殺を命じる
なぜです
Why?! Chidori's here, isn't she?!
千鳥はここにいるんでしょう
君が知る必要はない
You have no need to know.
Drop your weapon and surrender.
武器を捨て　投降しろ
バカな
This can't be...
You should do as he says.
言う通りにしたほうがいいよ
レナード・テスタロッサ
Leonard Testarossa...
Where's Chidori?!
千鳥はどこだ
"Chidori, Chidori, Chidori."
You never make any progress at all.
千鳥千鳥千鳥と
まったく進歩がないな　君は
ミスタ・ゴールドの部隊が接近中です
Mr. Gold's forces are approaching.
Meaning he's revealed his true nature.
We're short on time.
本性を現したわけだな
時間もない
So, what do you intend to do with him?
それで　彼をどうするつもりか
Dispose of him.
処分します
Very well.
結構
There you have it, Sousuke Sagara.
そういうわけだ　相良宗介
本気か
Are you serious?
"Try and stop me"?
私を止めてみせろ　だと？
Why shouldn't I have to reach to you no more?
What should I do have it reach to you?
'No more' -furious, stiff winds have made my voice stopped
furious, stiff winds have made my voice stopped
Why should we do fight and what we're ahead for?
You live as if you're dead all
and even love is hurt and broken altogether
Who in the world has done away with you into the end of world? yeah
Who in the world has done away with you into the end of world?
yeah
Can I see you?
The only thing I see is that I want to
hold a shining rise, held in your arms
hold a shining rise-held in your arms
and feel all to the last breath of my life
Can I be true?
No matter what I take, it's true that I'm sure to
miss dear face, your lasting trace
see your face, your lasting trace
Though I have nothing sure for you
Though I have nothing sure for you.. oh there's a hope
Uh There's a hope will reach to you -at least- 'yes'
will reach to you at last, yes.
本当にいいんですね
You're sure you want to do this?
Fine by me. That guy's the only one
who can operate this, anyway.
かまわない　どうせこいつはあの男にしか扱えないのだ
宗介が死んじゃってたら
What if Sousuke's dead?
捨てようが壊そうが好きにすればいい
Then dump it, wreck it, do whatever you like.
それでいいんだったな
That's what you wanted, right?
Affirmative.
肯定です
Next time: "Make My Day."
次回　メイク・マイ・デイ